## LUO YAO | 罗垚

# 185 0151 3917 royluoyao@icloud.com



#### **Profile**

Mr. Luo has 10+ years professional experience in software development; Especially in Mobile/Web/Mini-program development; Have a good knowledge on Swift, SwiftUI, Combine; Also familiar with React, Flutter, Web3, BlockChain; Familiar with the development and usage of common Al tools; Have excellent analytical and problem-solving ability; Can finish development tasks independently;

#### **Experience**

## **HSBC | Full Stack Engineer**

2022.9 ~ Now

- ★ Developed and maintained iOS applications for Web3 platforms, focusing on decentralized applications (DApps) and blockchain integration.
- ★ Explored and implemented AI tools to enhance productivity and optimize workflows in software development processes. Focused on integrating AI-driven solutions to improve user experience and streamline operations.
- ★ Designed and implemented secure and scalable solutions for managing digital assets and transactions.
- ★ Utilized React for building responsive web applications that interact with blockchain networks.
- ★ Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define product requirements and deliver high-quality software.

# Porsche Digital China | Senior Engineer

2021.2 ~ 2022.2

- ★ Participated in building the Porsche China APP architecture, responsible for the
- ★ development of the core business of the charging, responsible for the new
- ★ development of the payment function, the structure integration with the overseas
- ★ team, and the upgrade and maintenance of the Porsche dealer app.

★ Coordinate the communication between the App team and other teams.

# PwC | iOS Tech Lead.

2016.2 ~ 2021.2

- ★ He has served as the tech lead, developing iOS mobile applications for a foreign medical institution, completing modules such as UI development, data persistence, back-end data transfer, and HealthKit data reading, and completing speech recognition and interaction based on Siri and Amazon Lex module.
- \* He has independently upgraded and maintained enterprise CRM mobile applications for a large multinational retail company, and completed Salesforce data synchronization, customer management, task assignment and other modules to provide technical support and data debugging services.
- ★ He has independently developed a SSO (Single Sign-On) mobile application for a large multinational pharmaceutical company, completing modules such as UI development, back-end data transmission, keychain storage and sharing, and providing better users for all applications on the same device of the company. Experience.

# Zendai Property | iOS Engineer.

2015.2 ~ 2016.2

★ Develop iOS mobile app according to the project requirements, completed three P2P financial applications for the company.

# Pactera | iOS Engineer

2014 ~ 2015

★ He has served as the main team member of project, developing enterprise-level iOS mobile applications for a large state-owned bank, including modules such as UI development, data communication with the back-end, and security verification to realize mobile-based financial services.

# RenrenPin Beijing | iOS Engineer.

2013 ~ 2014

\* Has served as iOS developer, developing social mobile applications for a startup, completing UI development, instant messaging, data persistence and other modules.

## Dahe Tech Zhengzhou | IT Support.

2010 ~ 2013

★ Company IT equipment deployment, upgrade, installation and maintenance of computers and peripherals

#### Education

Henan University — Bachelor's degree in Physics.

2005 ~ 2009

## MAIN PROJECT EXPERIENCE

# 2021.02–2022 Porsche China | Porsche Dealer (internal)

- ★ https://apps.apple.com/cn/app/id1492218590
- ★ Porsche provides hundreds of exclusive charging points and 200000 third-party
- ★ charging points to ensure that users can find the required charging station and
- ★ complete charging anytime and anywhere. At the same time, users can use the
- ★ reservation test drive function and Porsche used car valuation engine.
  The
- ★ owner can make an appointment for online maintenance / repair service.
   Taycan
- ★ owners can purchase different kinds of exclusive charging service packages that
- ★ meet their own needs to check the installation progress of household charging
- ⋆ piles.

#### Responsibility and contribution

- ★ Mainly responsible for the design and development of APP core charging module, the development of relevant payment function components, the development of Valet charging module, the upgrading and maintenance of dealer app, and the reconstruction of the overall project.
- \* Complete the design of the charging module, and successfully implemented the full charging processes: reservation, arriving at the parking, opening the ground lock, scanning QR code to charging
- ★ Implemented the modular integration of UnionPay payment SDK, which can be called in different business modules of the app to help users better pay relevant fees.
- ★ Complete the new version of the valet charging module and realize reconstruction to reduce the coupling degree.
- ★ As the main force, carry out the architecture migration and reconstruction of the overall project.

#### 2020.03-2020.11 Automatic Contact Tracing

\* ACT is a novel coronavirus pneumonia close contact tracking application. Through GPS, WiFi and BLE (Bluetooth Low Energy) signals, the company helps quickly identify users who have been closely

contacted with patients in authorized geographical fences. The project uses a cross platform solution based on ionic and angular

## Responsibility and contribution

- ★ Mainly responsible for IOS native module and geo fence module in ionic
- ★ Complete the integration of IOS firebase crash analysis \ messaging related functions
- ★ Continuous integration with Fastlane
- ★ Complete the logical implementation of some ionic related geofence modules and related page exhibitions.

# 2018.07-2020.01 Bodylogical

★ Bodylogical is a personalized health monitoring and analysis application. Through the scientific analysis of users' current health data, it can predict the future health status of the human body and determine the best action plan to optimize the health status of individuals or people.

# Responsibility and contribution

- ★ Mainly responsible for the construction of project architecture and the development of core functions
- \* Realize complex reading and processing of healthkit data
- ★ Display of 3D model in application based on scriview
- ★ Realize customized line chart and histogram based on aainfographics library
- ★ Analyze and troubleshoot the crash problem and complete the launch of various versions of IOS
- ★ Complete the project reconstruction according to the demand change to

#### 2017.05-2018.06 Vivas

#### https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/vivas-tx/id1208147046?mt=8

★ Vivas is a medical and health application that can help people understand nutrition information, exercise knowledge and treatment plans And related drugs, and track relevant health indicators.

# Responsibility and contribution

- ★ Mainly responsible for the construction of project architecture and core modules
- ★ Communicate with product manager, UI / UX and development team, clarify requirements, promote process, find problems and find solutions.
- ★ Design the main architecture of the app, develop the core functions, realize the data interaction with apple healthkit, and use coredata to realize the local storage of data.

- ★ Explore and learn the interactive use of voice, successively learn and complete the use and integration of azure Lius, Amazon lex and Siri in IOS, and successfully realize the project requirements.
- ★ Independently design and complete the development of customized UI controls for the project, and obtain good feedback.

# 2017.01-2017.05 Lilly login (Eli Lilly)

★ Lilly login is a password management and single sign on (SSO) iPad client developed for Lilly pharmaceutical.

#### Responsibility and contribution

- ★ Independently responsible for all application development
- ★ Hold regular teleconference with product manager to communicate and clarify requirements.
- ★ Independently complete the UI, network communication and function realization modules of the application.

# 2016.10-2016.12 WKCDA (West Kowloon Cultural District)

- ★ Responsible for application architecture, core development and overall control
- ★ Communicate with product manager, UI / UX and development team, clarify requirements, find problems and find solutions.
- ★ Design the main architecture of the app, develop the core functions, and coordinate other members of the team
- \* Review the project code, solve the bug and package it for the customer
- ★ Be responsible for the overall project schedule, risk control and process control

# 2016.03-2016.10 Briefcase (Pernod Ricard)

★ Briefcase is a customer relationship management iPad client based on salesforce SDK.

# Responsibility and contribution

- ★ Independently responsible for application upgrade and maintenance.
- ★ Hold regular teleconference with product manager to communicate product requirements.
- ★ Study the feasibility of new functions.
- ★ Independently complete the upgrade iteration of the new version and solve various difficult bugs which feedback by customers

#### 2013.07-2015.03 Bank of China - e-commerce Finance

★ The Bank of China has created a variety of financial applications to provide convenient payment methods and quickly find bank outlets, preferential merchants and ATM information.

# Responsibility and contribution

*	Responsible for IOS platform client development, associated debugging, testing, bug repair, code reconstruction and optimization of the project.